Preliminary guide to The Wilderness Society Northern Rockies Region records 1977-1982
Montana Historical Society Research Center
The Wilderness Society. Northern Rockies Region records
1977-1982
Montana Historical Society, Research Center Archives Archives 225 N. Roberts PO Box 201201 Helena MT 59620-1201 (406) 444-2681 mhslibrary@mt.gov
S9:3-6
Wilderness Society (U.S.). Northern Rockies Region (Helena, Mont.)
22 linear feet of shelf space
The Wilderness Society, a national environmental organization, had its Northern Rockies Region office in Helena, Montana, from 1977 to 1982. About 198e the office moved to Boise, Idaho. Collection consists of subject files compiled by employees Bill Cunningham and Phil Tawney concerning the Bureau of Land Management (BLM); the "Sagebrush Rebellion"; oil and gas development; Montana national forests; wilderness areas; wild and scenic river designations; etc.
by series
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition information available upon request
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the Montana Historical Society Archives catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search under these terms.
Wilderness areas--Montana
Conservation of natural resources--Montana
Montana--Politics and government
Montana
Civic Activism
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Correspondence Numbered Subject Files
  - Bill Cunningham Phil Tawney, 1977-1978 (Box 1-2)
- Subject Files
  - Bureau of Land Management, 1978-1981 (Box 3)
  - Bureau of Land Management "Sagebrush Rebellion", Oil and gas development, 1978-1981 (Box 4)
  - National forests: Beaverhead - Gallatin (Box 5)
  - National forests: Gallatin - Lewis and Clark (Box 6)
  - National forests: Lolo; miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Wilderness areas: Bob Marshall, Absoroka-Beartooth, etc (Box 8)
  - Issues and Legislation: S.393; other states, etc. (Box 9)
  - Issues and Legislation: geothermal, RARE II, Gallatin land trade, etc. (Box 10)
  - People and Organizations: A-M (Box 11)
  - People and Organizations: M-Z; The Wilderness Society internal files (Box 12)
  - The Wilderness Society internal files (Box 13-14)
  - Miscellaneous (labeled but unsorted) (Box 15-19)
  - Clippings (Box 19)
  - unsorted material, mostly 1981-1982 (Box 20)
  - unsorted material, mostly 1981-1982 (Box 21)
  - Grazing (Box 22)
  - unsorted (Box 23)